Once upon a time
in a faraway land
a young prince lived in a shining castle.
Although he had everything his heart desired
the prince was spoiled,
selfish and unkind.
But then, one winter's night
an old beggar woman came to the castle
and offered him a single rose
in return for shelter from the bitter cold.
Repulsed by her haggard appearance
the prince sneered at the gift
and turned the old woman away
but she warned him not to be deceived by appearances for beauty
is found within
and when he dismissed her again
the old woman's ugliness melted away
to reveal a beautiful enchantress.
The prince tried to apologize,
but it was too late
for she had seen that there was no love in his heart
and as punishment,
she transformed him into a hideous beast
and placed a powerful spell on the castle
and all who lived there.
Ashamed of his monstrous form
the Beast concealed himself inside his castle
with a magic mirror
as his only window to the outside world.
The rose she had offered
was truly an enchanted rose
which would bloom until his 21st year.
If he could learn to love another
and earn her love in return
by the time the last petal fell
then the spell would be broken.
If not,
he would be doomed to remain a beast for all time.
As the years passed,
he fell into despair and lost all hope
for who could ever learn to love a beast?
Little town,it's a quiet village
Ev'ry day like the one before
Little town full of little people
waking up to say
Bon jour!
There goes the baker With his tray like always
The same old bread and rolls to sell
Every morning just the same
Since the morning that we came
To this poor provincial town...
Good morning, Belle.
Good morning, Monsieur.
Where are you off to?
The bookshop.
I just finished the most wonderful story
about a beanstalk and an ogre, and...
That's nice. Marie! The baguettes. Hurry up!
Look, there she goes The girl is strange, no question
Dazed and distracted, can't you tell?
Never part of any crowd
'Cause her head's up on some cloud
No denying she's a funny girl, that Belle
Bonjour
Good day
How is your family?
Bonjour
Good day
How is your wife?
I need six eggs
That's too expensive
There must be more than this provincial life...
Ah, Belle.
Good morning.
I've come to return the book I borrowed.
Finished already?
Oh, I couldn't put it down.
Have you got anything new?
Not since yesterday.
That's all right. I'll borrow... this one.
That one? But you've read it twice.
Well, it's my favorite...
far-off places, daring sword fights
magic spells, a prince in disguise.
If you like it all that much, it's yours.
- But, sir...
- I insist. Well, thank you.
Thank you very much.
Look, there she goes That girl is so peculiar
I wonder if she's feeling well
With a dreamy, far-off look
And her nose stuck in a book
What a puzzle to the rest of us is Belle
Oh, isn't this amazing?
It's my favorite part because you'll see
Here's where she meets Prince Charming
But she won't discover that it's him
Till Chapter Three
Now, it's no wonder that her name means beauty
Her looks have got no parallel
But behind that fair facade
I'm afraid she's rather odd
Very different from the rest of us
She's nothing like the rest of us
Yes, different from the rest of us is Belle
Wow, you didn't miss a shot, Gaston.
You're the greatest hunter in the whole world.
I know.
No beast alive stands a chance against you
and no girl, for that matter.
It's true, Lefou, and I've got my sights set on that one.
The inventor's daughter?
She's the one...
the lucky girl I'm going to marry.
But, she... The most beautiful girl in town.
I know, but...
That makes her the best
and don't I deserve the best?
Well, of course. I mean, you do, but...
Right from the moment when I met her, saw her
I said, "She's gorgeous," and I fell
Here in town there's only she
who is beautiful as me
So, I'm making plans to woo and marry Belle
Look, there he goes, isn't he dreamy?
Monsieur Gaston, oh, he's so cute
Be still, my heart, I'm hardly breathing
He's such a tall, dark, strong and handsome brute
- Bonjour -Pardon - Good day -Mais oui
- You call this bacon? - What lovely grapes
- Ten yards -Some cheese
- 'Scuse me -One pound
I'll get the knife
Please let me through
- This bread -Those fish - It's stale -They smell
Madame's mistaken
There must be more Than this provincial life
Just watch, I'm going to make Belle my wife
Look, there she goes A girl who's strange but special
A most peculiar mademoiselle
It's a pity and a sin
She doesn't quite fit in
'Cause she really is a funny girl
A beauty but a funny girl. She really is a funny girl
That Belle... Bonjour,
bonjour.
Hello, Belle.
Bonjour, Gaston.
Gaston, may I have my book, please?
How can you read this?
There's no pictures.
Well, some people use their imagination.
Belle, it's about time you got your head
out of those books
and paid attention to more important things...
like me.
The whole town's talking about it.
It's not right for a woman to read.
Soon she starts getting ideas,
and thinking...
Gaston, you are positively primeval.
Why, thank you, Belle.
What do you say you and me
take a walk over to the tavern
and take a look at my trophies?
Maybe some other time.
What's wrong with her?
She's crazy.
He's gorgeous.
Please, Gaston, I can't.
I have to get home to help my father.
Good-bye.
That crazy old loon...
he needs all the help he can get.
Don't talk about my father that way.
Yeah, don't talk about her father that way.
My father is not crazy.
He's a genius.
Ooh! Papa?
How on earth did that happen? Doggone it!
Are you all right, Papa?
I'm about ready to give up on this hunk of junk.
You always say that.
I mean it this time.
I'll never get this boneheaded contraption to work!
Yes, you will
and you'll win first prize at the fair tomorrow.
Humph! And become a world-famous inventor.
You really believe that?
I always have.
Well, what are we waiting for?
I'll have this thing fixed in no time.
Hand me that, uh...
dog-legged clincher, there.
So, did you have a good time in town today?
I got a new book.
Papa, do you think I'm odd?
My daughter? Odd?
Where would you get an idea like that?
Oh, I don't know.
It's just that I'm not sure I fit in here.
There's no one I can really talk to.
What about that Gaston?
He's a handsome fellow.
He's handsome, all right,
and rude, and conceited, and...
Oh, Papa, he's not for me.
Well, don't you worry 'cause this invention's
going to be the start of a new life for us.
I think that's done it. Now, let's give it a try.
It works!
It does?
It does! You did it!
You really did it!
Hitch up Philippe, girl.
I'm off to the fair!
Good-bye, Papa. Good luck.
Good-bye, Belle,
and take care while I'm gone.
We should be there by now.
Maybe we've missed the turn.
I guess I should have taken...
Wait a minute.
Let's go this way.
Come on, Philippe,
it's a shortcut. We'll be there in no time.
This can't be right.
Where have you taken us, Philippe?
We'd better turn around.
Whoa... Whoa, boy, whoa, whoa, Philippe. Oh!
Oh, look out!
Whoa, boy!
Back up, back up, back up!
Good boy, good boy. That's it. Back up!
Steady, steady.
Now, steady.
Philippe, no!
Philippe.
Oh... Help! Is someone there?!
Oh! Help!
Oh...
Poor fellow, must have lost his way in the woods.
Keep quiet; maybe he'll go away.
Is someone there?
Not a word, Lumiere; not one word.
I don't mean to intrude,
but I've lost my horse
and I need a place to stay for the night.
Oh, Cogsworth, have a heart. Shh!
Of course, Monsieur, you are welcome here.
Who said that?
Over here.
Where?
Allo.
Incredible.
Well, now you've done it,
Lumiere. Splendid, just peachy. Ah!
How is this accomplished?
Put me down at once! Stop that!
Stop that, I say. Ow!
Huh... Close that at once.
Do you mind?!
I-I beg your pardon.
It's, it's just that I've never seen a...
Oh, you are soaked to the bone, Monsieur.
Come, warm yourself by the fire.
Thank you.
No, no, no.
You know what the master will do if he finds him here.
I demand that you stop right there.
Oh, no, no! Not the master's chair.
I'm not seeing this!
I am not seeing this!
Well, hello there, boy.
What service. All right, this has gone far enough.
I'm in charge here.
How would you like a nice spot of tea, sir?
Lt'll warm you up in no time.
No. No tea. No tea!
His mustache tickles, Mama. Oh!
Hello. Uh-oh. Oh... Ah...
There's a stranger here.
Master, allow me to explain.
The gentleman was lost in the woods.
He was cold and wet...
Master, I'd like to take this moment to say
I was against this from the start.
It was all his fault.
I tried to stop them, but would they listen to me? No.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
I-I-I was lost in the woods, and, and...
You're not welcome here!
I-I-I'm sorry.
What are you staring at?!
N-Nothing.
So, you've come to stare at the Beast, have you?!
Please, I meant no harm!
I just needed a place to stay.
I'll give you a place to stay.
Oh, no! Please! Oh, no!
Oh, boy, Belle's going to get the
surprise of her life huh, Gaston?
Yep. This is her lucky day.
I'd like to thank you all for coming to my wedding.
But first I'd better go in there and propose to the girl.
And you, Lefou...
now, when Belle and I come out that door...
Oh, I know, I know!
I-I strike up the band.
Not yet!
Sorry.
Gaston. What a pleasant surprise.
Isn't it, though?
I'm just full of surprises.
You know, Belle, there's not a girl in town
who wouldn't love to be in your shoes.
This is the day... Hmm. Yeah.
This is the day your dreams come true.
What do you know about my dreams, Gaston?
Plenty. Here, picture this:
A rustic hunting lodge
my latest kill roasting on the fire
and my little wife,
massaging my feet
while the little ones play on the floor with the dogs.
We'll have six or seven.
Dogs?
No, Belle!
Strapping boys, like me.
Imagine that.
And do you know who that little wife will be?
Let me think.
You, Belle.
Gaston, I'm...
I'm... speechless.
I really don't know what to say.
Say you'll marry me.
I'm very sorry, Gaston, but...
but...
I just don't deserve you. Whoa!
So, how'd it go?
I'll have Belle for my wife.
Make no mistake about that!
Touchy.
Is he gone?
Can you imagine?
He asked me to marry him.
Me,
the wife of that boorish, brainless...
Madame Gaston, Can't you just see it?
Madame Gaston, His little wife
No, sir,
not me,
I guarantee it
I want much more than this provincial life
I want adventure in the great, wide somewhere
I want it more than I can tell
And for once it might be grand
To have someone understand
I want so much more than they've got planned.
Philippe! What are you doing here?
Where's? Where's Papa? Where is he,
Philippe? What happened?
Oh, we have to find him.
You have to take me to him.
What is this place?
Philippe, please! Steady!
Steady.
Papa.
Couldn't keep quiet, could we?
Just had to invite him to stay, didn't we?
Serve him tea.
Sit in the master's chair.
Pet the pooch.
I was trying to be hospitable.
Hello? Is anyone here?
Hello?
Papa?
Papa? Are you here?
Mama, there's a girl in the castle.
Now, Chip, I'll not have you
making up such wild stories. Really, Mama.
I saw her.
Not another word. But... Into the tub.
Woop...
Well! I saw a girl in the castle!
See? I told you.
Irresponsible, devil-may-care,
waxy-eared, slack-jawed...
Papa?
Did you see that?
It's a girl!
и笵琌
I know it's a girl. Don't you see?
She's the one...the girl we have been waiting for.
She has come to break the spell!
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Papa?
Hello? Is someone here?
Wait!
I'm looking for my father. I...
That's funny.
I'm sure there was someone.
L-ls anyone here?
Belle?
Papa!
H-How did you find me?
Oh, your hands are like ice.
I have to get you out of there.
Belle, I want you to leave this place.
Who's done this to you?
No time to explain. You must go! Now!
I won't leave you!
What are you doing here?
Run, Belle!
Who's there? Who are you?
The master of this castle.
I've come for my father.
Please let him out.
Can't you see he's sick?
Then he shouldn't have trespassed here!
But he could die.
Please, I-I'll do anything.
There's nothing you can do.
He's my prisoner.
Oh, there must be some way I can...
Wait!
Take me instead.
You?!
You would... take his place?
Belle, no!
You don't know what you're doing!
If I did, would you let him go?
Yes.
But you must promise to stay here forever.
Come into the light.
No, Belle!
I won't let you do this!
You have my word.
Done!
No, Belle, listen to me.
I'm old. I've lived my life.
Wait.
Belle! Wait!
No, please spare my daughter. Please!
She's no longer your concern.
Take him to the village. Let me out!
Please let me out! Let me out!
Please! Oh, please!
Master?
What?
Since the girl is going to be with us
for quite some time
I was thinking that you might want to offer her
a more comfortable room.
Then again, maybe not.
You didn't even let me say good-bye.
I'll never see him again.
I didn't get to say good-bye.
I'll show you to your room.
My room?
But I thought...
You want to stay in the tower? No.
Then follow me.
Say something to her. Huh? Oh.
I, uh, hope you like it here.
The castle is your home now,
so you can go anywhere you like
except the west wing.
What's in the west?
It's forbidden!
Now, if you need anything
my servants will attend you.
Dinner. Invite her to dinner.
You will join me for dinner.
That's not a request!
Who does she think she is?
That girl has tangled with the wrong man.
No one says no to Gaston.
Darn right.
Dismissed, rejected...
publicly humiliated.
Why, it's more than I can bear.
More beer?
What for?
Nothing helps.
I'm disgraced.
Who, you?
Never!
Gaston, you've got to pull yourself together.
Gosh, it disturbs me to see you, Gaston
Looking so down in the dumps
Every guy here'd love to be you, Gaston
Even when taking your lumps
There's no man in town as admired as you
You're everyone's favorite guy
Everyone's awed and inspired by you
And it's not very hard to see why
No... one's... Slick as Gaston
No one's quick as Gaston
No one's neck's as incredibly thick as Gaston
For there's no man in town half as manly
Perfect, a pure paragon
You can ask any Tom, Dick or Stanley
And they'll tell you whose team
They prefer to be on, Ooh!
No... one's... been like Gaston
A kingpin like Gaston
No one's got a full cleft
In his chin like Gaston
As a specimen, yes, I'm intimidating
My, what a guy, that Gaston
Give five "hurrahs!" Give 12 "hip-hips!"
Gaston is the best and the rest is all drips
No... one... Fights like Gaston
Douses lights like Gaston
In a wrestling match, nobody bites like Gaston
For there's no one as burly and brawny
As you see, I've got biceps to spare
Not a bit of him scraggly or scrawny That's right
And every last inch of me's covered with hair
No one hits like Gaston
Matches wits like Gaston
In a spitting match,
nobody spits like Gaston
I'm especially good at expectorating
Ptooey! Ten points for Gaston!
When I was a lad
I ate four dozen eggs
Every morning to help me get large
And now that I'm grown I eat five dozen eggs
So I'm roughly the size of a barge
No... one... Shoots like Gaston
Makes those beauts like Gaston
Then goes tromping around wearing boots like Gaston
I use antlers in all of my decorating
My, what a guy, Gaston!
Help! Help! Someone help me!
Maurice? Please, please! I need your help.
He's got her... He's got her locked in the dungeon.
Who?
Belle. We must go.
N-Not a minute to lose.
Whoa! Slow down, Maurice.
Who's got Belle locked in a dungeon?
A beast! A horrible,  monstrous
beast.
Is it a big beast? Huge!
With a long ugly snout?
Hideously ugly.
And sharp, cruel fangs?
Yes, yes.
Will you help me?
All right, old man.
We'll help you out.
You will?
Oh, thank you.
Thank you. Thank you! Oh! Oh!
Crazy old Maurice.
He's always good for a laugh.
Crazy old Maurice, hmm? Crazy old Maurice... hmm.
Lefou, I'm afraid I've been thinking
A dangerous pastime... I know
But that wacky old coot is Belle's father
And his sanity's only so-so
Now the wheels in my head have been turning
Since I looked at that loony old man
See, I promised myself
I'd be married to Belle
And right now, I'm evolving a plan
If I...
Yes?   Then we...
No! Would she?
Guess! Now I get it!
Let's go!
No... one... Plots like Gaston
Takes cheap shots like Gaston
Plans to persecute harmless crackpots like Gaston
So his marriage we soon will be celebrating
My, what a guy! Gaston!
Will no one help me?
Who is it?
Mrs. Potts, dear.
I thought you might like a spot of tea.
But you're... you're a... Ooh!
Careful.
This is impossible.
I know it is. But here we are.
I told you she was pretty, Mama, didn't I?
All right, Chip, now, that'll do.
Slowly now. Don't spill.
Thank you.
Want to see me do a trick?
Chip!
Oops. Sorry.
That was a very brave thing you did, my dear.
We all think so.
But I've lost my father,
my dreams... everything.
Cheer up, child.
It'll turn out all right in the end.
You'll see. Oh, listen to me.
Jabbering on while there's a supper
to get on the table.
Chip!
Bye.
Well, now,
what shall we dress you in for dinner?
Oh, let's see what I got in my drawers.
Ooh! How embarrassing.
Ah, here we are.
You'll look ravishing in this one.
That's very kind of you,
but... I'm not going to dinner.
Oh, but you must.
Dinner is served.
What's taking so long?
I told her to come down.
Why isn't she here yet?
Oh, try to be patient, sir.
The girl has lost her father
and her freedom, all in one day.
Master, have you thought
that perhaps this girl could
be the one to break the spell?
Of course I have.
I'm not a fool.
Good!
So, you fall in love with her,
she falls in love with you
and poof! The spell is broken.
We'll be human again by midnight.
Ooh, it's not that easy, Lumiere.
These things take time.
But the rose has already begun to wilt.
Oh, it's no use. She's so beautiful,
and I'm... Well, look at me!
Oh, you must help her to see past all that.
I don't know how.
Well, you can start by making yourself more presentable.
Straighten up. Try to act like a gentleman.
Ah, yes. When she comes in
give her a dashing, debonair smile.
Come, come, show me the smile.
But don't frighten the poor girl.
Impress her with your rapier wit.
But be gentle.
Shower her with compliments.
But be sincere.
And above all... You must control your temper!
Here she is!
Good evening.
Well, where is she?
Who? Oh.
The girl, yes.
The... girl.
Well, actually,
she's in the process of...
Circumstances being
what they are... She's not coming.
What?!
But, Your Grace!
Your Eminence!
I thought I told you to come down to dinner!
I'm not hungry.
You come out, or I'll...
I'll... I'll break down the door!
Master... I could be wrong,
but that may not be the best way
to win the girl's affections.
Please attempt to be a gentleman.
But she is being so difficult.
Gently, gently.
Will you come down to dinner?
No.  Hmm?  Ah, ah, ah!
Suave, genteel.
It would give me great pleasure
if you would join me for dinner.
We say please.
Please.  No, thank you!
You can't stay in there forever!
Yes, I can.
Fine. Then go ahead and starve!
If she doesn't eat with me,
then she doesn't eat at all.
Oh, dear.
That didn't go very well at all, did it?
Lumiere, stand watch at the door
and inform me at once
if there is the slightest change.
You can count on me, mon capitan.
Well, we might as well go downstairs
and start cleaning up.
I ask nicely, but she refuses.
Well, what does she want me to do...
beg?
Show me the girl.
Well, the master's really not so bad
once you get to know him.
Why don't you give him a chance?
I don't want to get to know him.
I don't want to have anything to do with him!
I'm just fooling myself.
She'll never see me as anything...
but a monster.
It's hopeless.
Oh, no!  Oh, yes!
Oh, no!
Oh, yes, yes, yes!
I've been burned by you before.
Zut, alors! She has emerged!
Come on, Chip, into the cupboard
with your brothers and sisters.
But I'm not sleepy.
Yes, you are.
No, I'm not.
I work and I slave all day long
and for what?
A culinary masterpiece gone to waste.
Oh, stop your grousing.
It's been a long night for all of us.
Well, if you ask me, she was just being stubborn.
After all, he did say please.
But if the master doesn't learn to control that temper
he'll never break...
Splendid to see you out and about, Mademoiselle.
I am Cogsworth,
head of the household.
This is Lumiere.
Enchante, cherie.
If there's... Stop that! ...anything we... Please!
Can do to make your stay more comfortable.
I am a little hungry.
You are? Hear that?
She's hungry.
Stoke the fire.
Break out the silver. Wake the china.
Remember what the master said.
Oh, pishposh.
I'm not about to let the poor child go hungry.
All right, fine.
Glass of water, crust of bread, and then...
Cogsworth, I am surprised at you.
She is not a prisoner.
She's our guest.
We must make her feel welcome here.
Right this way, Mademoiselle.
Well, keep it down.
If the master finds out about this
it will be our necks.
Of course, of course.
But what is dinner without a little music?
Music?
Ma chere mademoiselle.
It is with deepest pride and greatest pleasure
that we welcome you tonight.
And now we invite you to relax.
Let us pull up a chair
as the dining room proudly presents...
your dinner.
Be... our... guest, Be our guest
Put our service to the test
Tie your napkin 'round your neck, cherie
And we provide the rest
Soup du jour, Hot hors d'oeuvres
Why, we only live to serve
Try the gray stuff, It's delicious
Don't believe me, ask the dishes
They can sing, they can dance
After all, Miss, this is France
And a dinner here is never second best
Go on, unfold your menu
Take a glance and then
You'll be our guest, Oui, our guest,
Be our guest
Beef ragout, cheese souffle
Pie and pudding en flambe
We'll prepare and serve with flair
A culinary cabaret
You're alone and you're scared
But the banquet's all prepared
No one's gloomy or complaining
While the flatware's entertaining
We tell jokes, I do tricks
With my fellow candlesticks
And it's all in perfect taste, that you can bet
Come on and lift your glass
You've won your own free pass
To be our guest... If you're stressed
It's fine dining we suggest...
Be our guest, be our guest
Be our guest!
Life is so unnerving
For a servant who's not serving
He's not whole without a soul to wait upon
Get off!
Ah, those good old days when we were useful
Suddenly, those good old days are gone
Ten years we've been rusting
Needing so much more than dusting
Needing exercise, A chance to use our skills
Most days we just lay around the castle
Flabby, fat and lazy
You walked in and oops-a-daisy!
It's a guest, it's a guest!
Sakes alive, well, I'll be blessed
Wine's been poured, and thank the Lord
I've had the napkins freshly pressed
With dessert, she'll want tea
And, my dear, that's fine with me
While the cups do their soft-shoeing
I'll be bubbling, I'll be brewing
I'll get warm, piping hot
Heaven's sake, is that a spot?
Clean it up, we want the company impressed
We've got a lot to do
Is it one lump or two?
For you, our guest
She's our guest, She's our guest
People, fun's over, over here, line up...
It's ten years since we've had anybody here
And we're obsessed
With your meal, with your ease
Yes, indeed, we aim to please
While the candlelight's still glowing
Let us help you, we'll keep going
Course... by... course, One by one
Till you shout, "Enough, I'm done!"
Then we'll sing you off to sleep as you digest
Tonight you'll prop, your feet up
But for now, let's eat up
Be our guest, be our guest
Be our guest, Please be our guest!
Bravo! That was wonderful.
Thank you. Thank you,
Mademoiselle. Good show, wasn't it?
Yes, everyone.
My goodness, look at the time.
Now it's off to bed, off to bed.
Oh, I couldn't possibly go to bed now.
It's my first time in an enchanted castle.
Enchanted!
Who said anything about the castle being enchanted?
It was you, wasn't it?
I figured it out for myself.
I'd like to look around, if that's all right.
Oh, would you like a tour?
Wait a second, wait a second.
I'm not sure that's such a good idea.
We can't let her go poking around
in certain places, if you know what I mean.
Perhaps you'd like to take me.
I'm sure you know everything
there is to know about the castle.
Oh, well, actually, I, uh... Yes, I do.
As you can see, the pseudo-facade was stripped away
to reveal a minimalist rococo design.
Note the unusual inverted vaulted ceilings.
This is yet another example of
the late neoclassic baroque period.
And, as I always say
if it's not baroque, don't fix it.
Uh, where was I?
As you were.
Now, then, if I may draw your attention
to the flying buttresses
above the...Uh, Mademoiselle?
What's up there? Where? There?
Oh, nothing. Absolutely nothing
of interest at all
in the west wing. Dusty, dull, very boring.
Ah, so that's the west wing.
Nice going.
I wonder what he's hiding up there?
Hiding?
The master is hiding nothing.
Then it wouldn't be forbidden.
Perhaps, uh, Mademoiselle would like to
We have exquisite tapestries
dating all the way back to...
maybe later.
Th-The gardens or-or the-the-the-the library, perhaps.
You have a library?
Yes, oh, indeed.
With books.
Scads of books! Mountains of books!
Forests of books!
- Cascades! - Longboats!
Swamps of books!
More books than you'll
ever be able to read in a lifetime.
Books on every subject ever studied,
by every author
Why did you come here?
I'm... I'm sorry.
I warned you never to come here.
I didn't mean any harm.
Do you realize what you could have done?!
Please, stop.
Get out!
No!
Get... out!
Where are you going?
Promise or no promise
I can't stay here another minute.
Oh, no, wait, please.
Please wait.
Here now. Oh, don't do that.
Just hold still.
That hurts!
If you'd hold still, it wouldn't hurt as much!
Well, if you hadn't have run away
this wouldn't have happened!
If you hadn't frightened me, I wouldn't have run away!
Well, you shouldn't have been in the west wing!
Well, you should learn to control your temper!
Now hold still.
This might sting a little.
By the way,
thank you. For saving my life.
You're welcome.
I don't usually leave the asylum
in the middle of the night
but he said you'd make it worth my while.
I'm listening.
It's like this.
I've got my heart set on marrying Belle
but she needs a little... persuasion.
Turned him down flat.
Everyone knows her father's a lunatic.
He was in here tonight
raving about a beast in a castle.
Maurice is harmless.
The point is,
Belle would do anything
to keep him from being locked up.
Yeah. Even marry him.
So you want me to throw her father into the asylum
unless she agrees to marry you.
Oh, that is despicable.
I love it!
If no one will help me
then I'll go back alone.
Yes, is that everything?
I don't care what it takes.
I'll find that castle, and somehow
I'll get her out of there.
Belle? Maurice?
Oh, well.
I guess it's not going to work after all.
They have to come back sometime.
And when they do,
we'll be ready for them.
Lefou...
don't move from that spot
until Belle and her father come home.
But, but, I...
Aw, nuts.
I've never felt this way about anyone.
I want to do something for her. But what?
Well, there's the usual things.
Flowers, chocolates.
Promises you don't intend to keep.
Ah, no, no.
It has to be something very special.
Something that sparks her interest.
Wait a minute!
Belle,
there's something I want to show you.
But first, you have to close your eyes.
It's a surprise.
Can I open them?
No, no. Not yet.
Wait here.
Now can I open them?
All right.
Now.
I can't believe it!
I've never seen so many books in all my life!
You-You like it?
It's wonderful!
Then it's yours.
Oh, thank you so much.
Oh, would you look at that!
I knew it would work.
What? What worked?
It's very encouraging.
Isn't this exciting?
I didn't see anything.
Come along, Chip.
There's chores to be done in the kitchen.
But what are they talking about? What's going on?
Come on, Mom.
There's something sweet
And almost kind
But he was mean
and he was coarse and unrefined
And now he's dear,
and so unsure
I wonder why I didn't see it there before
She glanced this way I thought I saw
And when we touched, she didn't shudder at my paw
No, it can't be, I'll just ignore
But then she's never looked at me that way before
New and a bit alarming
Who'd have ever thought that this could be?
True that he's no Prince Charming
But there's something in him
That I simply didn't see...
Well, who'd have thought?
Well, bless my soul, Well, who'd have known?
Well, who indeed? And who'd have guessed
They'd come together on their own?
It's so peculiar, We'll wait and see
A few days more
There may be something there
that wasn't there before...
You know, perhaps there is Something there
that wasn't there before
What?
There may be something there
that wasn't there before.
What's there, Mama?
I'll tell you when you're older.
Right, then! You all know why we're here.
We have exactly 12 hours, 36 minutes and 15 seconds
to create the most magical
spontaneous, romantic atmosphere
known to man or beast. "Or beast..."
Right.
Need I remind you
that if the last petal falls from this rose
the spell will never be... broken!
Very well. You all know your assignments.
Half of you to the west wing.
Half of you to the east wing.
The rest of you, come with me.
Oh, lighten up, Cogsworth,
and let nature take its course.
It's obvious there's a spark between them.
Yes, but there's no harm in fanning the flames.
Besides, they must fall in love
tonight if we ever expect to be human again.
Ah, human again.
Human again.
Yes, think what that means.
I'll be cooking again, Be good looking again
With a mademoiselle on each arm
When I'm human again, Only human again
Poised and polished and gleaming with charm
I'll be courting again, Chic and sporting again
Which should cause several husbands alarm
I'll hop down off this shelf
And tout de suite be myself
I can't wait to be human again
When we're human again, Only human again
When we're knickknacks and whatnots no more
When we're human again, good and human again
Oh, cherie, won't it all be top drawer?
I'll wear lipstick and rouge
And I won't be so huge
Why, I'll easily fit through that door
I'll exude savoir faire, I'll wear gowns,
I'll have hair, It's my prayer to be human again
When we're human again, Only human again
When the world once more starts making sense
I'll unwind, for a change, Really? That'd be strange
Can I help it if I'm t-t-tense?
In a shack by the sea, I'll sit back, sipping tea
Let my early retirement commence
Far from fools made of wax
I'll get down to brass tacks and relax!
When I'm human again
So sweep the dust from the floor
Let's let some light in the room
I can feel, I can tell
Someone might break the spell any day now
Shine up the brass on the door
Alert the dust pail and broom
If it all goes as planned
Our time may be at hand any day now
Open the shutters, and let in some air
Put these here, and put those over there
Sweep up the years of sadness and tears
And throw them away
We'll be human again, Only human again
When the girl finally sets us all free
Cheeks a-blooming again
We're assuming again
We'll resume our long lost joie de vivre
We'll be playing again, Holidaying again
And we're praying it's ASAP
We will push, we will shove
They will both fall in love
And we'll finally be human again...
For never was a story of more woe
Than this of Juliet and her Romeo.
Could you read it again?
Well, here, why don't you read it to me?
Uh, all right. Uh...
Uh... I can't.
You mean, you never learned?
I learned... a little.
It's just been so long.
Well, here, I'll help you. Let's start here. Here.
Okay, "Twoe..."  "Two."
"Two... I knew that.
Two households..."
We'll be dancing again
We'll be twirling again
We'll be whirling around with such ease
When we're human again, Only human again
We'll go waltzing those old one, two, threes
We'll be floating again, We'll be gliding again
Stepping, striding as fine as you please
Like a real human does,
I'll be all that I was
On that glorious morn when we're finally reborn
And we're all Human again!
Tonight is the night.
I'm not sure I can do this.
You don't have time to be timid.
You must be bold, daring.
Bold, daring.
There will be music... romantic candlelight...
provided by myself.
And when the moment is right
you confess your love.
Yes, I con...
I-I... No, I can't.
You care for the girl, don't you?
More than anything.
Well, then, you must tell her.
Voila! Oh, you look so... so...
Stupid.
Not quite the word I was looking for.
Perhaps a little more off the top?
Your lady awaits.
Tale as old as time
True as it can be
Barely even friends
Then somebody bends
Unexpectedly
Just a little change
Small, to say the least
Both a little scared
Neither one prepared
Beauty and the Beast
Ever just the same
Ever a surprise
Ever as before
Ever just as sure
As the sun will rise
Tale as old as time
Tune as old as song
Bittersweet and strange
Finding you can change
Learning you were wrong
Certain as the sun
Rising in the east
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast.
Off to the cupboard with you now, Chip.
It's past your bedtime.
Good night, love.
Belle?
Are you... happy here with me?
Yes.
What is it?
If only I could see my father again
just for a moment. I miss him so much.
There is a way.
This mirror will show you anything...
anything you wish to see.
I'd like to see my father,
please.
Papa?
Oh, no. He's sick.
He may be dying
and he's all alone.
Then, you must go to him.
What did you say?
I release you.
You are no longer my prisoner.
You mean... I'm free?
Yes.
Oh, thank you.
Hold on, Papa.
I'm on my way.
Take it with you
so you'll always have a way to look back
and remember me.
Thank you for understanding how much he needs me.
Well, Your Highness,
I must say everything is going just swimmingly.
I knew you had it in you.
I let her go.
Yes, yes. Splen...
You what?
How could you do that?
I had to.
Yes, but... Why?
Because... I love her.
He did what?
Yes. I'm afraid it's true.
She's going away?
But he was so close.
After all this time,
he's finally learned to love.
That's it, then.
That should break the spell.
But it's not enough.
She has to love him in return.
Now it's too late.
Papa! Papa!
Ooh. They're back.
Belle?
It's all right, Papa. I'm home.
I thought I'd never see you again.
I missed you so much.
But the Beast?
Did you... how did you escape?
I didn't escape, Papa.
He let me go.
That horrible beast?
But he's different now, Papa.
He's changed somehow.
Oh. A stowaway.
Why, hello there, little fella.
Didn't think I'd see you again.
Belle, why'd you go away?
Don't you like us anymore?
Oh, Chip, of course I do.
It's just...
May I help you?
I've come to collect your father.
My father?
Don't worry, Mademoiselle.
We'll take good care of him.
My father's not crazy.
He was raving like a lunatic.
We all heard him, didn't we?
No, I won't let you.
Belle? Maurice,
tell us again, old man.
Just how big was the beast?
He was... I mean, he was... he was... enormous.
I-I'd say at least eight...
No, more like ten feet.
Well, you don't get much crazier than that.
It's true, I tell you.
Get him out of here.
Let go of me.
No!
You can't do this.
Poor Belle.
It's a shame about your father.
You know he's not crazy, Gaston.
Hmm, I might be able to clear up this...
little misunderstanding.
If... If what?
If you marry me.
What?  One little word, Belle.
That's all it takes.
Never.  Have it your way.
Belle.  Let go of me.
My father's not crazy and I can prove it.
Show me the Beast.
Is it dangerous?
Oh, no, no, he'd never hurt anyone.
Please, I know he looks vicious,
but he's really kind and gentle.
He's my friend.
If I didn't know better
I'd think you had feelings for this monster.
He's no monster, Gaston.
You are.
She's as crazy as the old man.
The Beast will make off with your children.
He'll come after them in the night.
No!  We're not safe
till his head is mounted on my wall.
I say we kill the Beast!
We're not safe until he's dead
He'll come stalking us at night
Set to sacrifice our children
To his monstrous appetite
He'll wreak havoc on our village
If we let him wander free
So it's time to take some action, boys
It's time to follow me
Through the mist, through the woods
Through the darkness and the shadows
It's a nightmare, but it's one exciting ride
Say a prayer, then we're there
at the drawbridge of a castle
And there's something truly terrible inside
It's a beast, he's got fangs,
razor-sharp ones
Massive paws, killer claws, for the feast
Hear him roar, see him foam
But we're not coming home
Till he's dead, Good and dead, Kill the Beast!
No, I won't let you do this.
If you're not with us, you're against us.
Bring the old man.
Get your hands off me.
We can't have them running off
to warn the creature.
Let us out!
We'll rid the village of this beast.
Who's with me?
Raise your torch, mount your horse
Screw your courage to the sticking place
We're counting on Gaston to lead the way
Through the mist, through the wood
Where, within a haunted castle
Something's lurking that you don't see every day
It's a beast, one as tall as a mountain
We won't rest till he's good and deceased
Sally forth, tally ho
Grab your sword, grab your bow
Praise the Lord, and here we go.
We'll lay siege to the castle
and bring back his head!
I have to warn the Beast.
This is all my fault.
Oh, Papa, what are we going to do?
Now, now.
We'll think of something.
We don't like what we don't understand
In fact, it scares us And this monster
is mysterious at least
Bring your guns, bring your knives
Save your children and your wives
We'll save our village and our lives
We'll kill the Beast!
I knew it was foolish to get our hopes up.
Maybe it would have been better
if she'd never come at all.
Could it be?
Is it she?
Sacre bleu! Invaders.
Encroachers.
And they have the mirror.
Warn the master.
If it's a fight they want, we'll be ready for them.
Who's with me?
Take whatever booty you can find
but remember, the Beast is mine!
Lights ablaze, banners high, We go marching into battle
Unafraid, although the danger just increased
Raise the flag, sing the song
Here we come, we're 50 strong
And 50 Frenchmen can't be wrong
Let's kill the Beast!
Pardon me, Master?
Leave me in peace.
But, sir, the castle is under attack.
Kill the Beast! Kill the Beast!
This isn't working.
Oh, Lumiere,
we must do something.
Wait, I know.
Kill the Beast! Kill the Beast!
What shall we do, Master?
It doesn't matter now. Just let them come.
Kill the Beast! Kill the Beast!
Kill the Beast!
Now!
Yes!
Here we go.
What the devil?
Belle, look out!
You guys got to try this thing.
Up here you scurvy scum!
Now!
And stay out!
Get up.
Get up!
What's the matter, Beast?
Too kind and gentle to fight back?
No!
Belle...
No! Gaston,
don't!
Let's go, Philippe.
Come on out and fight!
Were you in love with her, Beast?
Did you honestly think she'd want you
when she had someone like me?
It's over, Beast.
Belle is mine!
Let me go. Let me go.
Please, don't hurt me.
I'll do anything. Anything!
Get out.
Beast!
Belle?
You came back.
You... You came back.
Of course I came back.
I couldn't let them...
Oh, this is all my fault.
If only I'd gotten here sooner.
Maybe... it's better...
it's better this way.
Don't talk like that.
You'll be all right.
We're together now.
Everything's going to be fine. You'll see.
And... at least...
I got to see you... one last time.
No. No.
Please... Please...
Please, don't leave me.
I love you.
Belle. It's me.
It is you.
Lumiere.
Cogsworth!
Mrs. Potts!
Look at us.
Mama, Mama.
My goodness.
It is a miracle.
L'amour.
Well, Lumiere, old friend.
Shall we let bygones be bygones?
Of course, mon ami.
I told you she would break the spell.
I beg your pardon, old friend
but I believe I told you.
No, you didn't... I told you.
You most certainly did not
you pompous, paraffin-headed peabrain.
En garde, you-you overgrown pocket watch.
Take that.
Are they going to live happily ever after, Mama?
Of course, my dear.
Of course.
Do I still have to sleep in the cupboard?
Certain as the sun
Rising in the east
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast
Tale as old as time
Song as old as rhyme
Beauty and the Beast.
THE  END